GOVIND SINGH

Present Address:

House No. 129, Sarita Vihar,

New Delhi – 110076 Mobile: 9540662330

E-mail: govindsmehta@gmail.com

SYNOPSIS

A dynamic professional with extensive experience in HRM/Administration/Operations broadly People Management skills, Recruitment, Performance Appraisal, Compensation, Training & Development, Policies & Procedures, General Administration and Personnel Management.

Worked with Architects, Builders & Promoters, Automobile, Manufacturing, IT/ITES, FOREX/BFSI and Facility management sectors.

Educational Qualification:

P.G. diploma in "Personnel Management and Industrial Relations"	' from All India Institute of Management
Studies, Chennai in 2010.	

- B. Com. from Dr. Bhim Rao Ambedkar University in 2000.
- One year Diploma in Computer Applications in 1997.

Professional Experience:

Current Employer : Tecknomen Facility Services (P) Ltd.

Duration : March 2020 to till date

Designation : Manager – HR

Key Result Areas:

Manpower Planning and Recruitment:

- Managing Pre & Post Recruitment process for PAN India, Face to face rounds, Salary structuring and negotiations, Training & Development, and Manpower Planning.
- ➤ Identification of various channels for sourcing and recruitment (Naukri.com, Consultants, Job sites, walk-ins, referrals, advertisements etc.)

Generalist & Employee Relations

- ➤ Handling Induction, joining formalities e.g., Joining report, PF & ESI, and other employment registration forms, ensuring submission of all the required documents by the employees at the time of joining.
- ➤ Coordination with bank people to open bank account for new joiners.
- > Personal details of employee for generation of employee codes and uploading on Intranet portal.
- ➤ Coordination and distribution of Temporary/Permanent ID, Training and Visitors cards & configuration of Biometrics/Access cards.
- ➤ Preparation and distribution of Offer Letters, Appointment Letters, Appraisal Letters, Movement Letters/Transfer Letters, Address Proof, Acknowledgment of Resignation, Relieving, and Experience Letters.
- ➤ Preparation and Maintenance of Personal Files of all levels, generate reports of MIS & HRIS of new employees, left employees on Intranet portal.
- Arrangements and coordination for various indoor and outdoor activities on various occasions like Birthday celebration, Anniversary, National Festivals, etc.
- > Coordination for ISO and ISMS internal, external and HR audits.

Performance Appraisals:

- > Conducting performance appraisal exercise.
- Performance Appraisal Process follow-up and co-ordination, preparation of increment plan and increment letters.

Payroll, Compliance & Compensation Management:

- > Responsible for collection of attendance from different departments/processes in PAN India and maintenance of employees leave records for salary preparation.
- ➤ Handling employee's queries regarding salary issue.
- ➤ Keeping records of Leaves, Absenteeism and Late Coming.
- Taking care of PF, ESIC and Medical facilities.
- > Processing of left employee's PF withdrawal form.
- Liaising with Government department regarding renewal of various labour licences, PF office, ESI office and Labor office as and when required.

Employee Exit

- Taking care of exit formalities, both voluntary and involuntary exit.
- > Conduct exit interviews and perform analysis of the same to identify issues and work towards resolving them.
- Final settlement processing and issuance of Relieving/Experience letters to exit employees.

Administrative Management

- Planning & budgeting of administration expenses and working towards minimizing the operational expenses/costs.
- ➤ Taking care of Cafeteria, Housekeeping and stock management.
- Taking care of all Vendor Management (Cafeteria, Housekeeping, Stationery and Printing, Building maintenance, Air conditioners, Furniture, Electrician, Plumber, Courier, ID card and other miscellaneous vendors),

Previous Employer : R.R. Sen & Bros. (P) Ltd.

Duration : August 2019 to February 2020

Designation : Manager – HR & Administration

Previous Employer : M.B.A. Consulting India Pvt. Ltd.
Duration : December 2017 to July 2019
Designation : Senior Team Leader - H.R.

Previous Employer : Ienergizer IT Services Pvt. Ltd.
Duration : March 2011 to November 2017
Designation : Assistant Manager - H.R.

Previous Employer : Innodata Isogen Pvt. Ltd.

Duration : June 1999 to March 2011

Designation : Production Associate

Expected Salary : Negotiable

Notice Period : Negotiable

Ready to Relocate : YES

DATE: PLACE:

(GOVIND SINGH)